{
  "age": 57,
  "background": "Owned and Operated Bill's Seafood and Catering Co for 38 years.",
  "directory": "content/state-house/district-7",
  "district": 7,
  "dob": "8/9/1961",
  "education": "Perry Hall High School",
  "filename": "bill-paulshock.md",
  "full-name": "Bill Paulshock",
  "jurisdiction": "Baltimore County",
  "last-name": "Paulshock",
  "party": "Republican",
  "questions": [
    {
      "question": "Do you support the findings of the Commission on Innovation and Excellence in Education? Are you committed to funding associated reforms, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "We need to allow teachers to teach and not parent or police our children. We need to create a safe learning environment our children. Teachers need to be able to educate our children and not just teach them how to pass tests. Teachers also needs the proper tools and supplies to educate our children. We need less bureaucracy and more education. The commission wants to increase spending and we need to guarantee that the bureaucracy is eliminated and the money is spent for the proper objectives.",
      "shortname": "Kirwan"
    },
    {
      "question": "Is Maryland’s transportation spending appropriately balanced between roads and transit? Does the state have the resources to meet its transportation needs? With the cancellation of the Red Line and the advent of BaltimoreLink, is the Baltimore region adequately served by transit?",
      "answer": "The Transportation Trust Fund has enough money to support the current system. We have to make sure the fund is not used for anything else. We need to be efficient and make sure that the systems in place are adequate and always look for improvements.",
      "shortname": "Transportation"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the legalization of recreational marijuana?",
      "answer": "No, only medical.",
      "shortname": "Marijuana"
    },
    {
      "question": "At a time when the federal government’s commitment to Chesapeake Bay restoration is questionable, what new steps should Maryland take to protect this resource?",
      "answer": "As someone who has made their living from this most valuable resource, I believe we should do anything possible to restore and protect the Chesapeake Bay. From  saving the areas biggest natural resource; the Man O'War Fossil Shell Shoal  from dredging which would destroy the habitat for rockfish, crabbing, oysters and other valued species to cleaning and protecting the bay. I would support any measures that protect this resource.",
      "shortname": "Chesapeake Bay"
    },
    {
      "question": "What steps should Maryland take to ensure the broadest possible access to affordable health care?",
      "answer": "The entire health-care system needs reform. We need to bring down costs to companies and individuals. We need to improve access to care so everyone has coverage. We need to have competition in the marketplace that will  help to drive down costs.",
      "shortname": "Health Care"
    },
    {
      "question": "What role should the state play in helping Baltimore address violent crime?",
      "answer": "The State of Maryland holds the responsibility for the safety of all of it's citizens.  The Governor needs to work in tandem with the Mayor to bring down the murder rate and make our streets safer. Violent offenders need to be sentenced appropriately. We need to develop strategies that are effective to deal with repeat offenders. We need to create programs that support our youth so that better opportunities are available other than lives of crime.",
      "shortname": "Crime"
    },
    {
      "question": "How would you characterize Maryland’s business climate? What can the state do to foster the creation of more family-supporting jobs?",
      "answer": "I believe that small business is the back bone of this great state.  Maryland's job growth has exceeded the national rate, We need to increase incentives to bring new businesses  to the communities of  Maryland and reduce the burdensome regulations and taxes that plague small business.",
      "shortname": "Business Climate"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you support the creation of a non-partisan, independent body to draw legislative and congressional district maps after each census?",
      "answer": "The process of redistricting should be conducted by an independent commission with all stakeholders represented.",
      "shortname": "Redistricting"
    },
    {
      "question": "Does the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the public? Should it be changed, and if so, how?",
      "answer": "There is a fine line between regulating police authority and allowing the police to enforce the law, while protecting civil liberties. This is a complex and difficult job. I feel that the Law Enforcement Officers Bill of Rights adequately balance protections for police and the citizens. Our first responders are the most important service in helping and protecting our communities and ensuring their safety.",
      "shortname": "LEOBR"
    },
    {
      "question": "What strategy would you adopt to address the opioid addiction and overdose crisis?",
      "answer": "I would educate both the prescribers  and the pharmacies  to alternatives to opioid use. When opioids are absolutely necessary, laws should be in place to restrict the quantities. All first responders should have access to naloxone.",
      "shortname": "Opioids"
    },
    {
      "question": "What if anything should the state do to address income inequality?",
      "answer": "In any free society, income inequality is a necessary component of an effective capitalist economy. No state should intervene. Instead resources should be directed to helping the poor by providing education for economic advancement.",
      "shortname": "Income inequality"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do the state’s Public Information Act and open meetings laws adequately ensure Marylanders’ ability to exercise oversight of the government?",
      "answer": "The Public Information Act  was created to ensure accountability to the public. While the act should operate effectively not enough is done when violations occur.  We should have stricter consequences for offenders.",
      "shortname": "Transparency"
    }
  ],
  "race": "state-house",
  "residence": "Kingsville",
  "survey-response": true,
  "title": "Bill Paulshock"
}
